SHARAFATH ALI

Full Stack Developer [React.js & Node.js]

Marafathaliofficial@gmail.com

(\) +91 9946164265

<u>sharafathalivk</u>



sharafath-ali



<u>Kochi, Kerala</u> - India

Profile

Software Engineer with close to 2 years of experience in full-stack development using the MERN stack and TypeScript. Proficient in building and optimizing web applications, implementing new features, and addressing real-time client issues. Experienced in Agile methodologies, cloud services (AWS), and backend enhancements.

Skills

- React.Js
- Node (Node Js)
- Express (Express Js)
- JavaScript
- TypeScript
- MongoDB, Mongoose
- jsonwebtoken (JWT-based authentication)
- bcrypt (Secure password hashing)
- REST APIs
- Model-View-Controller (MVC)
- Socket.IO
- SHARE POINT FRAMEWORK
- · Server-Side Rendering (SSR) with EJS
- Git
- Postman
- Redux-Toolkit
- Azure Devops
- GitHub
- React Router
- Styled Components Sass
- Microsoft Windows Series, Linux
- HTML, CSS
- Material-UI, Chakra-UI, React-Bootstrap
- · Debugging and troubleshooting

Education Background

Bachelor of Computer Applications

Jamia Hamdard Kannur Campus, Kerala Jamia Hamdard University, Delhi 2019 to 2022

• 12 th (Higher Secondary Education)

G.V.H.S. School, Kadirur, Kannur, Kerala Kerala State Board 2017 to 2019

10 th (SSLC)

Kuthuparamba High School, Kannur, Kerala Kerala State Board 2017

Certifications

- Programming with JavaScript
 View Certificate
- Back-End Development with Node View Certificate
- WebDiary Academy's ReactJS Course

Professional Experience

Associate Software Engineer

1st September 2023 to 30th September 2024 (1 year 1 month)

Associate Software Engineer trainee

27th March 2023 to 30th August 2023 (5 months)

Global Infonet Inc, Kochi

Global Infonet Inc is a SharePoint Consulting Group focusing on Sharepoint. Their main product is Dock365, a contract management system, built on SharePoint and React.

Key responsibilities:

- Initiated and successfully completed the development of the transformative Quick Link feature in Dock 365's Contract Management System (CMS) 4.7 release. This innovative addition, comprised of 28 strategically integrated panels throughout the system, empowers users to effortlessly access and edit related entity details directly from an entity, eliminating the need for redirection. This enhancement significantly amplifies user efficiency and elevates the overall user experience.
- implemented various features and resolved critical bug fixes, leading to a substantial enhancement in the performance and functionality of Dock 365's Contract Management System (CMS).
- · Collaborated with teams to deliver high-quality solutions.
- · Actively participated in team meetings and code reviews.
- Worked in feature enhancements by implementing more userfriendly design and workflows.
- · Worked in UI overhaul.
- Tested and reviewed code to meet standards and improve quality.
- Active participation in feature analysis and suggestions.

App Link

Personal Projects

HR-PORTAL App

- Streamlines employee management with features like adding/updating information, file uploads, and managing notes.
 Ensures data accuracy, security, and a user-friendly HR experience.
- · Tech Stack: React.js, Material-UI, SASS, Express.js, SharePoint.

GitHub Repository

Chat App

• Responsive web chat application allowing people to communicate, powered by React, Sass, Material-UI, Express, and Socket.IO.

Website Link GitHub Repository

Flim-flix App

 Flim-flix is a responsive web application that provides comprehensive details about various films, powered by React, Sass, Material-UI, and the TMDB API.

Website Link GitHub Repository